Although.
We didn't see their hi welcome to ask net deep
...this is part...of what was started yesterday with
...hunter this is now demean edwards.
Damien owns...dot net and we're going to go deeper into what we talked about yesterday so hopefully
just disturbingly yes,...click...micro works...is not will give that...my quizzical
...that's article awesome ...you are code
okay all right...supposed to do something with we look at and marvel...the technologies.
All right and that's this...they
...everybody that button.
Or maybe this other...
that one...over eight so that's a good okay and that's a command from because that's what
we want to the...to small...window...make.
Sure, I can zoom okay because this is...so we can start looking at the command-line...might
...hyping most people he today when you look...introduction...leasing some of a gone...before this is
the dee-ee going straight in so when you install visual studio twenty fifteen ossie you're going to get something
on your path which is something called the in vm dot net version manager
...aspects of based on at five and dn x which is what we've built
...on top of is ability run-up different versions of dot net include
...and dot net core different businesses...mono those type of things so I can look at
...a list and this gives me a lot nicest of the things I currently have a machine I think you so
this yesterday to my...profile you can see the location there with all that stuff is?
But, there are couple of the commands as well.
So, we have
dn x this is the command used actually execute your application right and you can see here
...variables generally need to say what...is my program indian xdot-f
doing in the local folder and what command is that you want to run that's pretty much all this does?
Then you have been you d new is sort of
where everything else goes is the utility of how you build...how you package
it's how you create a deployment artifacts and you can pusher websites or might thing is it doing the work or
...it like shell out other things it doesn't work internally but the shared card so, for example, if you do a
deanne your stall that's using new get under the covers...what is...for new
...new get but they'll be sort of a one-to-one with what new get the new version of new get free...to
do and what...you can do in terms of restore...you can do more...its intended for the next
the client of...then a whole bunch of other exactly...and you get and it's also a whole bunch of other stuff...
okay so when you choose which version of the and actually going to use it affects which
ones of these commands...using so, if I go back to dane the list?
actually...correctness I'm within back in here you can see the currently I have one
...ob to...eighty-six mocked is active now on your machines when you
install twenty fifteen ossie this will not be the case your command-line if I go over to the right
...you will have an alias...called default I think you showed this yesterday the
...text files often my in that same...that you can see
them right so in order to set one is being active all I have to say is zoom back then
...screen because I'm getting too close to the bottom xmt used
to fault that will set that alias dn x version as my current
...x for this section for this command pro this command prompt and you can see that of
a scroll over...has been to process pop ok,
so, if I want to make that assistant I want to use this version for
evermore does that mean I could open to command proms and run beta this and beta that
...absolutely...time yep absolutely I
can say dsp and this time add that to my path both the process pop in the use of
part user not the system not the systemwe do have a flagging
strategy for system but we don't generally recommend that generally this be doing this of the use
...level all right so I could change if I wanted to I could say if I go back and say the
...list and then I say...vm say use one-dot...
dot net have to use...alias where I can to say I want to use...full and I want to use
...runtime course the a-law instead of being the full sealer...often...
next someone now it's going to be using the...because I didn't deduct paper closes and come back in
...active and I can prove that becoming...one...we'll see a code.
Visual, visual...encoding...because into gigantic did you guys download visual studio code
author moi.
Thank you so they can't hear the audience on the recordings so...really just
...demeanor...pretty much so like we'll tell a joke and it
is lance flat so there I...back to active-x out and you command from my...still one that was that
persistently...the course...and this course euler's...and mono is
a thing too when I was the thing too I have...I set up here and also have dev ones set
up here because I've cloned the...source code with a little bit about later on and I've
...command that sets up so that I can want to development version of the next ok so that's like
the well...over...of these three command-line you'll have to get familiar with will use them a little bit more
...as we go through and do some other things in the talks so let's go over to and
that now let's talk a little bit about finding...an entry point?
And, what that means so we have a...dot net consul application you'll know that when you compile
you can executable and...double-click that you probably have a
...understanding what happens right...a...the exes the tells the operating system is a managed exes
a to boot-up...on the os those that for-you and,
then you executable runs what is a...is a possible program...a static
void mythical...you'll often hear fehler and us talk about the study would main...
deciding what makes device that's just a convention like the thing runs because we've always and public that
equipment correct so we have a...about equivalence as well...and I didn't use that
...noun use a web right now but if you using a consulate that...be or entry point by default that
study void main which gets created in that class in a web application which is what I've created here?
You have something slightly different you have this startup class now you would have seen this if you
use any of ecbatana stuff from previously focus any other demos using phrase but on
the five in this world the boot-up in the startups logic is a little bit different each...again,
my project jason farm you'll notice that I have commands registered my
...involved I think again you told us yesterday so these commands are
actually specifying entry points...application okay because a web...doesn't have a study void entry
points plural entry points plural, yeah, so, by default and this one I just have web
because I chose empty going to run this on the command-line any to say well how do I started as I
...would main a microsoft based on that hosting is a dependency
uphold environment get package it has inside of it effectively a study void
...so I can configure...when I drop down the command-line by can run
dn xdot-f web them the command and that will be use of my entry point now the acinet
...hosting application
effectively is like russian build nesting okay it knows how to find
...designed web application so...looking for you'll start-ups
...based on convention and booting up your application by doing this up and running those
...methods so the name startup is meaningful the...startup is meaningful ok so that's the publish
...main for internet four-h...if you configure these commands...you can
...other commands as well so we saw ef yesterday so if you've ever use the
new get consul manager to do like...commands migrations from our
...we have a command-line equivalent of that now written on top of this...a little one of those
later ones you could see how easy to do them so when I run this from the command-line
...this morning the same app in different ways just like I can get into my house from the front...side or,
yeah, exactly so absolutely I...obviously new get in...packages that contained commands
will do that later on as welland, you can...commands inhibit them so let's talk a little bit about di.
So, tendency inject dependency injection ioc sometimes...control and,
when we talk about the think generally we have the concept of container that's the thing
that sort of where all the things that I want to be dependency injected live that's where the
registered and it's also with things that once staff task taken you give me something that looks like this
type of food okay now we have
...baked in dn x which underlies
...on it so I can use the online this application let's do
...season previous versions of...lots of more can advanced developers would say in
...control dependency injections really important they would bring in all sorts of
dependence injection systems yep you can bring those in here as well but we think that
...injections becoming mainstream yes so it is bacon...by hafta u
...really audiences you really...it if you really, really don't want to you...new objects
...file...up but if you want to get certain intrinsic from the system that are already being managed by
...you need to get from us so that's starts write-up...startup
you need to get something from the system like I want to...by application environment somatic...here?
I can say I need there's a interface that I note is provided by
aid dean...tells me a little bit about the applications as it's running...but the in
...that if and then I'm going to assign that to a variable called
...controlled again to slaving typing generate on-the-field so this is a standard sort of
...dependency injection...and there are certain points in a dn...five application
where you can do this because you think about what's happening here this will only work on classes that are being
new...someone who knows how to do this...this type activation
by the way that everyone like you have to...slow-motion again at home but it's kind of
...he push control dot online eighteen on...line fourteen
...generated that's one of those little things words like how did I never not always know that yes it will
save you like six hours a week especially if you start doing these types of patterns of constructor
indefinitely so this interface what...worth is one this provided by
...of...chips and it gives you things like the base...and what current environment and you're running in those type of things
...of your app et cetera et cetera so I can inject stuff into my
stop-off because that's what we bring you can also inject stuff into things like nbc control is into
...of views and also into tag help...that will show...of
...very quickly because that's kind of interesting on a create a...a larger application...one has no
So, we have a new feature in razor while this is restoring I'm
going to go into thisnow I'm not going to stop the religious debate about whether it's
correct or not to dependency inject things directly into the view...
will say is that personally views have their own logic may not be business logic but there's
...logic involved in composing the html that gets
...to the client sometimes you need to have services abstract elements of that logic
okay so not everything always comes through the model because it may have nothing to do with the actual data
...but not architectures up to you do it make you happy but we now have a new ang angular
...you raise a...which let-you inject things from the
...container directly into your view anything,
anything, anything...been registered in the I contain a can be placed in his
...the same thing here.
Application an I'll call then the second name hiya is
I property name so I have to add a using obviously because I haven't done that I can do
that directly in this file now I could also do that in the global import
...to make this using everywhere previously...web...which is kind of
horrible this microsoft dot framework dot something,
something, something which I can't remember right now the top my...over
...other is over in the other thing, you know, what I can cheat?
Because we don't have controlled unfortunately so I can do this.
And, I can do that like the...there is always very close committee
...process and here.
And, now I'll get is an app and property in my page of adopt
...type happens you'll see now I actually have that property dynamically generated in my
...rate even...the you...compile this and you're not running it right now
I razors re smart figured out was because we pulled up to roles and behind-the-scenes in autopsy stuff going on
behind the scenes nice so the reason this is quite interesting is because alba based class
...view pages now is not as heavy as it used to be just like
...control is now just a class with a bunch of stuff depends injected in...base class arrays of
uses pretty much the same...a base class that has a bunch of at injects by default the
...doesn't even have the html property it's
just at injected into that at runtime by default so it means if you
want to override the html property I could call this html.
Now why would I do that but now my html is negation
will help anymore it's my application environment I don't have to change the base
...to change the opinions about the type of things that we ship in the box is what will happen when it
was before a lot more...and this is the thing...all about choice if you don't like some aspect of this
as a subsystem that you've offends you putting your own
...system I...subsystem I'm offended by logging...
they well what is speaking of my logging.
Control is obviously another place we might want to do dependency injection
...so the kind of finishes outlets of look at how I would do that and add-on basically the same thing I did
...constructor...taking the log...constructor...I want to property injection yes.
Meaning attacker...you do anything you want to out-of-the-box constructor injections what we do are
...other di containers that you can inject that you can configure...one of the can be property injection
who condemn we support all of those things awesome so I'm...and I...which is a new interface that we
have...acinet five...the next doing lugging.
Has configure will...and, you know,...goodness so I'm going to same thing
...longer is equal to log...factory dot create log out?
And, I'm going to do it for my harm control now this is just a convenience
method this generic method basically crates me a logo whose name is this
...important when you...generally blogger category elec who
...this so you can very simply just do this and now I have this
...I don't have to...and a hard coded string...the high...you know,
I could just that's cool so then I can say control dots what...did before generated read-only
...I change my focuses...work...now I've got my...here and I could look something out of...
one-c ok so that's dpi in a nutshell so sometimes when I'm playing with
asp net I feel like in your earlier versions even though the sources like a reference source and
...available...kind of feels like there's a wall between me and there,
yeah, sometimes I'll get like and open-source library drinking nbc I can step in I can see the
...I can't really change it...and this is...is one of the
sort of the bad things about a dot net general and...like saying that but you don't
...lot of great things but it also has...we compared to things like ruby and node which javascript this in
ship...source right so if you bring in something into...you have the source
that you need to...you just stepping in dot net we have things like
symbols and source stepping...ever tried to get dot net
...source stepping to work in visual studio who keep hand-up if...got to work regulate
...one two people have the hands-on so some of the things we've done eight-to-five indian
...thought about that...nice you've all seen the I change file
...vsi all go back of the browser hit five that a recompile that's one of those sort of
...do...show you next is something else that's kind of like that now this is actually
a story I was doing a workshop in new zealand last week and I want to show off a great
you tag help that we have called the...done...what idea an undue what I do here.
And, we can tell of course from your accent you're not from new zealand I'm not I'm from australia action
...sales and loads...living in going up so my accent is all over the place
but okay so I want to show of this new thing...cacti...I'm going to my index and...
okay let's create and each one and then I'm going to do something like a hello.
Date time dot now dot to the...
String okay and then let's duplicate that.
So, I can prove that one of them is...and one of them is
...and...a...the first one...this new cash tag helper.
That turn purple and that turned purple you can see that here right purple emboldened
...as an html...not that's a that's an element that I've created
all we've created and...a tag help us...one...cash tag this one's behavior is
a take everything inside of it and...memory cache again india has the normal things we
...to drill into this but you can do expires you can do very by
...things helper...help but if I just use it like this what I should see is that
when I run this out one of these will stay the same...the other...change every time I refresh right.
So, okay, fifty nine and then I hit a five and...
But, here in lies the story.
So, at this point I'm...I have, you know, thirty or forty...customers within a
...like crap why does this work this is the visual studio a-c this is that
...legitimately support I was legitimately surprised because, you know,
I just did file new and I uses great cash tag over one
...about and it doesn't work out-of-the-box some like what I normally do in the
...of...this thing and figure out what...what would...if you're at work if I was a work I'd go into the
...source solution and I'd open up that and then I try and figure...still working in
...now at this point I'm like well I know that works we have texts the...file we would've...the
...tag oper itself is broken but I still need to figure out how to debug this
We have a good feature for doing this now so we have this new global
jason file up and here is kind of like a quasi global
...has other things in it but it's at the solution level four-d
...right sort of application not a list of projects a list of places that stuff can be yet,
yeah, a couple...of...of the...I'm using those type of thing so I know I have the
nbc source here this is work on my stuff too and you can get that by this cloning go-to get hop
...get all that type of stuff and we are looking at building features to make what I'm about to do the next two minutes
one-click operation...visual studio because...keen about making this type of workload really,
really nice so now I'm going to do is going to come in here and
add that path that I know contains thebut,
I know contains the source code for nbc and I'm going to going here I'm going to change my
back slashes to...slashes because, you know,
for such as appearing pretty much every way but when you're in jason think it's better
... for...are better it's better when you're in jason because I like double back flushes and for such as
a cross-platform they cross-platform like that sql...node but thanks pointing that out.
Why did you into this talk I'm going to run this by myself?
People will turned up.
I...iq love having...love having okay so
...now people who...keen died may have noticed and stuff going on over
...solution explore things...moving...alive what's happened is I've added
extra place for it to do dependency resolution for...that means a big bunch of with
the nine-zero solution we don't generally think about the looking for stuff we just think about file
...reference right well if I go and look at my project
jason file these things are just names...reference nbc by nine-a version,
version is there as well but there's no pop I didn't say it was new get package I didn't say
...the deal...say was a project I just said...something with this name and
the process of dependency resolution which is what the next does is...out well is this
a project that I can load source card is and you get package I have to go download from a feed
or is it something else so because I've added that pop it can now load...source in a
...directly into my solution so this point I have the source code so I can just do
...tag help that was control...there's my cash tackle from vc
...go to the process method?
And, I put my bright point here and...up again and probably fails because I forgot
...restore but we'll see whether it hold my hand...tells me nope so I...come up here
into a manual restore right now is a bug is a blog right now in the way we do restore...this version
...ok.
But, the name inside of the project jason refer
to something he wanted and there's a whole chain of...could come from new get
...come from one of...new gets in his...could come from something local it could come from a local nigger on
the disk orchid come from source so he can basically get control of what level
...scoping of these projects yes so I can I'm just looking at the package
resort process right now I'm hoping the internet doesn't make a full of me so it's downloading stuff and
sometimes it a little...well if that happens
then we'll just debug that and then we'll use that story in the next talk,
yeah, we could do that what I might do just to speed this up you have
...the one we did last night now what I might do this...is going to turn off that feed.
The one the one you're not feeling good about...need that...
then I'm going to come in here ...open my...force.
...this is just like an...slow thing...okay.
As long enough to close it because it is stuck in the other one.
...open that up again.
And, the next the next version of new get has some speed features as well I understand, yeah, so,
...you get version free fade which...version doesn't support current...we have
...much...that's now restored probably my break point is to sets...five all right.
We nervous now I knew
was going on but I would have appreciated not losing that minute...that's okay.
About this minute right this minute right here where I wait for the...talking...ok so here I am inside.
Mike has tag of a semi function was...think...have passwords we generate
a key which...a big strain right and then we put something in there next time comes around we generate the key
again we ask the...you already have this autumn I was pretty confident was...indicate correctly
because like I said we have we have testing things so I figured what was this object here this memory
cache property this is dependency injected m...level talked about before and my hunch
was that this memory cache object wasn't going to be the same one when I read
a second time my hunch was that someone was replacing it each time the...couple
...memory caches...is one of them exactly these at least be shared between multiple
...right otherwise what you actually caching so I'm going to add that to my what to into here.
So, there's my memory...write...on that and...make object id okay so what
does the goal one after that and that's a unique instance
id for this object instance of that class how many people use make object id all the time.
Biif says eighty-seven now if you are now going to use rodent.
Okay.
Good night everybody welcome...will continue running the page I can see my bug is there and
...five again and look back to things have happened instantly make...the dollar
...is gone because that instance have an id this new one doesn't because I haven't...mass you put a
post-it note on that...right and that's a different guy that's a different guy so now I know I have a bob now
also went...which is what tells you...change between the two things right so,
I...the budget isn't in the...okay this point the bugs in the someone who setting up the
I so I can remove this bright point and we'll stop debugging and I'm going to go
often debug my startup process...debug the setting up all
...now this is one of the dirty secrets of using gis that you need
to understand what's going into the container throughput in there and what lifetime
...one-in-four so...show you quickly how you can derive the
...makes things easier but it doesn't allow you to be willfully ignore it's
layer of abstraction away from who's nearing up
objects you have to have an understanding of who's actually doing that especially when you hit issues like this so now I'm in my
startup method configuring the di container
with the things that can be resolved later...loggers memory you
boots database stuff all the things that one with all the things that the used by the systems imis
dot net okay so I'm going to pop the descriptive...this is my services its
...a private feel...descriptors...to add that to watch so there's nineteen
is nineteen things in there right now so these are just the things that came from the
dn x itself right...application environment I hosting environment...no there's no
...and I just nor because I know the system...eye-catching I could have looked about...that she logging
...I just all dances log in a couple of things I know this line doesn't do it because
it just adding one thing the container which is my...application the...we'll see that go up to twenty
which did so that now we get into the real meat and potatoes right now we're going to add entity framework
this is going-to at all the stuff required to get...my app so he has a lot of stuff well that was
a hundred...right this which is not a bad thing not...the middle talking
...databases nontrivial so now I'm going to scold I'm going to eyeball and scold down and gary
case somewhere in here microsoft data...leave a microsoft framework caching the
...there...memory...look?
Transient transients so there's the bob the blog is singly and what not
...singleton I wanted to be singled transit means every...a new and not every request that would be
...transit means anytime anyone asks for one so-if you could just
...to method calls give-me that and given yet again you get two different ones all right so I know with
the buggies nano I could bring in the...source code...tribe debug that but,
you know, what I know this stuff is on get hub I think at this point I could probably just go
up here and I can go up to the get hub?
...and I could actually...
...and then I could do a search up here and I just search for I memory
cache which is the interface that I know...places using I memory...all of the
...source code from and look at that transients zoom in so I'll find in
here okay...online memory cache there is?
there is the add transit memory...so they had a good problem for that but I'm like well now I know
with...is but I kinda understand how we got here because how do we ship with this
bug meeting we ship to the bugs we do that all the time we just human going to hit this button.
...might I did this last week when I was in new zealand and then I went...
this was done by andrew...a team lovely guy but he's a kiwi.
So, it was...of poignant that I was foiled by a kiwi while I was in...but,
this one I have the line of code I know where it is I went often created issue onstage on get...look here's a lot of
...publisher reviled above I thought about absolutely that's what people...do that's what people need to do
so I've used the tools that we've built...very easy to be the
...is the locking like we've hit bugs at work before like up what we're screwed...linux
...so then how to...one of my demo to work right so let's come back I know the part I know the problem is
...all have to do is get in before services dot
add singleton I memory cache...to bring that in?
Memory cash and that's it whoever gets to do at first because
...frameworks to a try add instead of an add they check to see if it's
...already because I'm going to add a singleton under...so now if I run that.
Compiling, compiling launching.
Thinking, thinking that we...to hartley this time when I hit a five what
...of change now we can see one of them says the same and one of them is actually...by the...but.
...to use what you would say
...the landing stick the landing the land nicely done sir we found the fan so, yeah,
there's some really.
I just want people to understand when we talk about building a get on
...five is open-source...the...dot net is opensource it's not just about the source being
...just about you being able to...building yourself make a changes
and contributions we want you to be able to feel like you're using open-source code that's your code as much as
it is...so we're going to improve this...little bit packing right now right because I like we're going to
references right click and say get that I imagine if I could
...and I a little new get...notice how it changed those are those arelocal, yeah, so,
that means project reference and the other one's a new get references now before I show...this I would've been a new get
reference...change but would be nice if I...write master...here and say switched
...osdbu...at.
That...do that...do that we'll do that we are.
This many behind okay so we'll do that...want to the
...that one...awesome all
rightsupposedly files I'm going to add a well we don't use...it's full of nbc now how...you get rid of it lots
...now...can do that just to be clear is literally two things together
that do that because we don't we don't need all the
...now and...that's it...it I'm...was it will get from you get...that was...of the references they switch
and a little nobody thinks they will have boom now they're back to
...so they...all right so let's add a applauding...the other room...
I feel...that a great job.
...labor it...little delay and...to get it is there any other from you to believe that was for
us just totally for...to believe that was rush
all right so we also have a new class library project okay and you notice this...class
library package this is a is a...are built on top of the exact same
project systemthat the dn...web project system is using isis omega
...jason not ac...projects...is actually the same...literally identical
...two things...them in one of them was a property...project site
...called web...told that this is where you find web files that was it otherwise it's just it's
a dn x project that's all it really is so I'm going to create one of these.
And, we'll call it class everyone because I can't think of a...name right now so, what's interesting about building
...services that this project produces a new get package now I can add a reference to
...as I would anything else I can come over here I can say add reference it looks just like it
does today I can I class one come over here it's familiar people...if I go down to project
...now you'll see that added classify everyone like as we said before it's just
the name doesn't know...point if it's a new get package or project...else but obviously gets result
...a package sorry as a project because I haven't next to my other project
...one of the things we do by default in both of our project templates
...my project jason look at this framework section
...collapse that our project system the...
x can build from multiple frameworks simultaneously who has ever had to build
the same source code against two sets of sort of dot net
worlds maybe windows phone and sphere dot net for five okay
...do that overwrite...go-between to o and three five...three five and you would do the if
there right...to glory if...you...worry absolutely but, the way you would do that
if you have one set of files and one project and you have a second project was set up as a like a...
project and you would link those falls into the other one you have to projects now
...solution only really only have one set of card well we've merged into one thing we've made
a first-class concept we borrowed heavily from the work done by
the universal projects system, you know, the...project stuff they did last year to get a local features
of that so if I come over here in my class we can see some of the benefits of the up here in the loop
that one up here in the top left in my csharp file I have the switch of the
let me switch context so for every framework that I add in my project...
file get a new context in fact if I come down here and let's say I also want to build this for net
four five one.
They say that.
Say that.
Notice now that dot net framework for five-one showed up in there so
now I'm compiling three times when I build this and the difference here is the using the
dn x environment on for five-one...versus just
four-by-one the way we write...next as a bunch of things a...also...so this is
...next booting for five-one and compiling about world versus the next booting difficult now
...the secret when you do it this way it's still the next doing just that uses a different set of references
...uses the real dot net for framework for five-one references
...ok so when I'm writing card this way though eventually I'm going to hits and
scenes and people often ask me so we have this dot net core thing we have dot...framework
...the new hardness it goes...linux...across platters portable it portable I can make
x copy...my app but doesn't have everything...the primary what happens if I hit one of the
...way something is missing...move something around so I happen to
know that there's one thing that we've moved around which is how you set the culture for the current thread
of internationalization, internationalization right so let's say in the constructor of this ridiculous
...okay so I could do thread?
...control dot now.
Look, at this.
Move this is interesting because we talked about how before
...framework was this monolithic right and now you literally saying that system
dot threading is just a piece it really is a cafeteria plan when you run dot net call when you're not
...yes so if I did using system dot threading this woodwork full
...yes...if I...to is everywhere I need to
pull in this package that lights up that frayed api on all the frameworks
...only ships and uses what it needs and nothing else
...that threading thing it doesn't even show up absolutely...here...go back to my project
...file there...threading...dependency of that thing down there okay so...current
...dot current culture but you'll night if you look at the intelligence here.
See it's giving me it's telling me...little warning triangle in the same completion
...saying hey this method is available in two of those frameworks
this property but not in the last one we call this combined
intelligence you're getting intelligence for all target frameworks at the same time while you're in
the file ok this then again these are all tools to help you in this world of...out on a
...dot net for five code okay over to dot net...building tools to help you do that how would I go
and figure out what I should do...panicking at this point I'm like well why need that so,
yeah, so, that's really good question at the moment the bringing in the...one
of the things we did so if we didn't have that you may be trying to using a will that api doesn't exist right where is
it in a package...in a word is we have that stuff in terms of the case here when you find
...api difference that...documentation right now which is a little early on because we're
...of things force but I can tell you I know-how to do that so I'm going to
say new culture infer and that's going to.
Experience...go and we'll do in-dash.
So, now I've got I'm saying the current culture to...trying build this project now.
But, note the project name movie here is thread does not contain a definition of
...project contexts project
...remember gave me the warning it said this...api isn't available on one of them so I
...I need to fixes I've hit one of those seams between the two well so I can use
...if there and I will admit this experience of
...isn't the best one I think we have a little bit of work to do here to make this
...really nice experience because if that's going to be a little bit more common now...I dn x
...fifty which is the symbol we used to represent when I'm on that
And, I'll do the rest of that down there so in this case of...is backwards
...need to move this code out of there.
And, put that down there okay and then I need to switch on a switch over to this context
dot nickel fifty...ethical fifty and wiser importance which content because not
...right this is one of the things I don't like about this experience right now what I
would rather do is if I put my clustering here that becomes the active context.
Yeah, so,
anyway, we're still working on this the right now you just kinda have to understand that you need to do
...sometimes you have to do I don't think I'm that smart I like it this way you like this way well if I
say I think that just by virtue of my cursor being in a different place I would confused, yeah,
I don't know so the other thing that you don't see right now is notice before when I had
this when I had this out of it when I had this of...yeah, if I move this outside you could just switch
context now I want actually move that into the on?
This is showing an error here because I switch...if I do this, you know,
what I want to see that squiggly even though I'm not in that context...I want to know
...have an...different-colored squiggly I could do a different colors
...visual studio card it does what I'm saying it actually shows you small...and
...for all target frameworks...compiling for the same time and actually think that's a
...better experience interesting but I digress let's put this back in here where I
note will work and then I happen to know that to do this on the and I want
...intelligence...you get...intelligence in your great text yes that's cool?
So, culture info is sitting already...get
pulled in the gi or where what let me switch context to get all that working in the
...against yank...because I mean there which I think is a little bit clumsy
sung and controlled up of icy okay that's a
valid point you didn't see anything no hint so I was like it works out because it's
grey and exotic freaking out...actually I got actually working and?
Now it's lying...getting a little angry...trying...I have reference
...that's interesting what does that mean so it means something went wrong during reference I'm going to delete
this to so I don't go...to
...script and we'll check out there...it's saying is
...is package...this package so I brought in a little bit too...get rid of that.
And, I'm going to say that.
I might be hitting a
...experience right now actually might be trying to bring the package into the wrongarea
...context into the wrong into too many places I'm going to put this down here so
that fixes...it's interesting because you've got dependencies which is everybody's design
nancy's and then under frameworks he's got dependencies just for this thing up so,
for example, if you were doing ...now we don't have a graphics generator
in core so let's say that you are doing check imaging for a bank or whatever and
then you're moving that over from full framework to core and like up I just had a seem you're
...to go and find a core framework library that does that imaging build
the layer of abstraction on top of it and then if...
around that you would have but you wouldn't want to take that library that new imaging library
and reference in the full framework version so that would become some that would go under the dependency so
you say the...dependencies...shared are here
...ones for this framework...here and the ones for...there so you're basically getting references
...that are specific to the target framework that you
want to use absolutely I think I have indexing bugging...tenets working in the same
...absolutely so what I've done here is I know I have in...this is the api
that use naps of the current culture and...actually does it come from it's just in threading...different namespaces
...mobilization like I'll...threading current culture that is the one that
...in...net today got...net nagel space something moved for some reason something we for good
reason and you can track these movements...team is being very good about publishing their api reviews
...good status documentation up...get hub where they talk about as a movie things around
...why that there's even some interesting videos where you can see the
...core team arguing about this
starts with new people...been the company a couple years and people in
a company fifteen twenty years some with historical context some with the future focus
arguing in a room with white board so if you like that kind of nerdy stuff we've got ours
...thanks to check out like twitch for developers,
yeah, is like...developers are not...coding we just young and we have...we have
Just...sit...okay so what I build this which so before we actually get anything when
we build this right...others no been...been debug right what's have a look so here's my
...folder right now here's my ideal how do I get stuff we'll do that and
...the properties of the project.
Then I go over to...
And, I take the magic...I'm sorry.
So, why would I want outputs on a build anyway because we build from source so, if I'm any of
the using this class library in the context of this solution there's no need for me to produce
I appreciate the design work that was done on this particular.
...what is the giant
...could a.
Okay, so, make stuff
...allocate you design meetings...we do this stuff okay it's not even like in the...
Okay, so, then when you hit control should be
...just appear so I built that now but...still hasn't turned up in there we actually build...different location now so,
I'm going to flip back is my root of my application notice artifacts folder so, we kind of
being opinionated about solution fold layout...x because we think this
is cleaner it also maps very well...if you just want to put this in something like
...hubble your source control what is a really nice it's funny you do that because when I was working in the
...with these large systems with twenty thirty forty solutions
...in debug benji might be and I would go and right like prune digital
...the on crap so we've made some decisions about where things go so there's my been folder
class everyone debug and there's my package...can see there's my dl but no that's not
even in there it's there's a new get...there's...deals other different folder now this is complaining that I
...filled in authoring description that's...at template so I can go and fix that
...project jason where you would have previously put these things in a new
spec file or in your assembly info file right it's combine now because new
gets and assemblies for the next or effectively the same so I don't even have to make a news...you don't have to make
...we do everything that you...do new spec is gleaned from this project...file...this
...build and will say that it's made by me mobile this again?
We'll go back here time step flips...again so here
...who uses nigger packages for everyone know about nigger package explore.
Ok, good...go get it
...click once application makes nice little icons...me to say this for your
...up kegs and ...how what you pronounce that.
That is not kagan any language my frame ogg.
Even american.
Okay, so, my new get package has inside of it those
two folders and the assemblies from the...I recognize those strings yes dan
x four five minding...those...meaningful they show everywhere...well-known...they're...they
...target framework monica's which is a fancy way of saying the name of the
framework compiling...okay the acronym we
...offends so if you ever look at...so you look at checking comments and stuff like that we talk about
...famines that's what we're talking about target framework monica's the names of the framework of compiling...so
...one...package so this point I can your push that...I can do whatever I want...that as I said if I
hadother target frameworks and him I could have multiple complicated you get package...looked at
...dot net it has like fifteen of these things and a bunch of portable...canonical
examples cystic if you go to the command-line new get install newton
software jason open up the zip file he's got...all that work but he went and had actually manually,
manually do all annual new spec file manual
...process take the deal allows move them into a separate folder during a script other
that brought a whole skip to do that the benefit is that you go into a project of any kind and you get
jason net and you get a good one and you don't think about it not just
works it just works all right so how would I do that from the command-line, you know, I just said you could do that as part of the
...process or something obviously going to do this and...so let's jump out to the
...jpm grab that path and come back here we'll do this.
...do that and windows ten you can control eigen now I don't have to the
...in the case stark anymore and they go in here whoops.
Okay, and, then here I can type dean you build.
That...does a build...really do anything it just
...I want to produce a package...you'll see the...you...
...you...so that does the same thing so...makes artifacts
...makes packages makes packages yes and you can see...here says
class everyone you build didn't make packages...you build random build and
...errors so checked so as you often say compilation is just the version
attest writer and that's what the new buildings
doesn't compile yes I don't want anything out of it just tell me...compiles and that's what
the new...nice ...you...as packages and you can see...put the path down there to now I can obviously
given extra argument which is where I want that to godel this type of things but the point is I can do that...is also makes
that dependency chain really nice because I used to work with all these large systems
...all those bins my bins would become someone else's lives
...their organization would build and they go into their bins and...would slow like that
...that dependency replication where I work so you have something that I depend on...replicate that over here
...I build something that he depends on the and goes on it all works and tell the one of the middle changes aversion number
while you forget to update that version whatever might be okay so that's class
libraries cool very cool let's jump into looking acts.
Let's...okay, because I know my boss and your boss promise
...to...time image that we promised yes...can be the finale.
So, I'm going to come back into this application the one I use the cash...before and I'm going to create attack helper.
Create a folder...tag helpers.
...is that important the name of now I mean this is just where you...put your...represents
...morning with...there's a lot of magic
string so it's important to remember what is a very good point I'll show you how you have to import these and just a moment
there's no convention for how we find those you have to actually declare where they are going to call this a
repeat tag helper and no prizes...guessing what it's going to so
...attack of a has to do is actually...interface we do have a base class.
But, if I just jump over to the interface who's ever tried to write I web forms control
...control and actual control who's ever done that one don't be afraid like
...been at sixteen years it's okay if you...waveforms control it's a safe place lots of people.
That's hard this is the interface for...
It hasn't order property because you...for element right and it has a process method
Promised everyone here is that we shall never add lifecycle method will be no
...needed a posts...and a pre render an ready...a data by and
...patrols then depraved what and the free
...workout...workout and then...laugh we actually have a pre in some places as well.
We have process okay that's all it is not web form this is not
waveforms you get a context which gives you details about the element that was in the
...html file the...running on in this case the
...within the cash element what's within you have output which
...okay and if there's more than one tag...currently running on an element which is...
the orders for these a stateful these...so they cascade from one tag
...into the other and that means you can write tackled was that actually coordinate with each other for more complex
scenarios...not going to go...that today we're going to a simple one just to get you started but let's go back
...a use the base class and...I'm going to come down here I'm going to override my process asic
methods matching to do something icing make this icing don't worry about calling anybody
...bybase methods even though we're using inheritance here about why we try to make this is the
...friction...possible...constructor you have to overwrought or anything like
...I'm going to add a property to here.
Is going to be it going to call it counts the put the
...ok so that's the minimum going to do for right now and then
we're going to go off and actually register this so little thing about naming by default
the html element name that this will...to is derived from the name of cosco
...a convention we strip the word tag help roughly
into a class and then we just take what was left so I have now created a repeats element if I
wanted to attached attributes instead I could do that as well I can...here
...target elements
...I could say attributes equals and I can say what I actually want to create one called like
dame a repeats and then this tag couple will apply to any element that has an attribute called
...repeat okay makes sense if you have these angular directives a
...similar to that I was greatly inspired by angle...server-side in this case
...all service...yep ok so we'll just leave this is a discrete
...elements for now I now have to tell...a way to find this I'm
...to go down to this new file global important explain a little bit about what that is so we all know what do
...right...code that runs in the view before anything else I think that
...to move?
Global import is way you can put...directives the get inherited by
or your views because what's induce start is imperative and what's
in global import is declarative okay directives in
...attribution this word direct is the things that affect...okay they don't make code
the effect how the file gets...a using statement is there because it gets added to the top and we
positive...to figure out what stuff you're calling and that tag help us says
okay when I'm pausing html elements check those element names attributes against these
tag help us okay so I have to add one of these my own so I called this web application fourteen.
So, I could make resource be helping...to help me when I
...mistakes before and I'm just looking...so,
I can make tag helpers produce artifacts give them to as
a nutcase to my coworkers and then they go in there and they use them
...consume yes absolutely you can put them in your package, for example, put them on internal feed
and maybe some of the community will make the great world's great by absolutely however that's what
happened so now that I've come back into my index the...html and I
type re note that I now get intelligence immediately for that so all those people who had built web
forms controls...with the vs editor to try and get them to show up after
you build them that just works first-time right now which is nice
...will get better...moment you have to close the file and reopen if you create a new tag
helper okay but I'm hoping that ...time we'll get a little bit so there's my
account property by property shows up...attributes...can change the name that with
...attribute and csharp possible...them and note that I declared as what and it
...string this is actual csharp...he control spicier.
I mean csharp.
So, tag...going fundamentally change...hang on.
Go ahead.
What is...as attempting language when it comes down to it right what defines attempting language has
...it has...opinionated way of doing something spock does something...enamel...something on my
...about taking csharp?
And, html...together with this few seems possible
that previously we did that with the app character you would say at blog you would call help
...would return golf and then of you would guard right we've just gone one step further and said why can't we
just go html attribute equals...have that blobby...
Without me having to switch transition...for tackles that's what we've done that we built in order to
...so this has to be here a number if I...something here that isn't
a number like date time dot now and I closes out so I can finish
wait while a generic who because it's csharp right.
So, let's go back here and I'm going to make this one now if I did have a
...declared...through whatever that would be in...could just...on the model whatever.
So, I have actually implemented anything yet right so let's go
...implement the rest of this help them.
Which is pretty straightforward so...I need to do is
...if counts?
Is...to that again from scratch if count?
Is less than equalizer I'm going to return that
...being nice and defensive otherwise I'm going to do a full loop and say for all?
And, I'm going to call back content equals
...on the context object that's passed in this method
hit get child content icing get
...all the content inside the element execute that
...now...executed get by the time this process methods running so that'll
...and they'll keep parsing and chaining everything together right and then let,
you know, at the last and then you'll do...you...to the whoever's above you so it's a stack and we
papa stack as we go down and...unwind through the hierarchy
...html elements now this method is...so it's only going to run once so I can just call it
...here...obviously...what memorized memo onbasically it's like...item
pardoned method you call it once...the same as you just explain a complicated word with another complicated work.
It...the result internally...
From now people can look up...one homework they...
All right we'll computer science...summing all right so
then I'm going to come in here and I'm going to actually append stuff to the outputs on
the output dot content dot append that content.
Now we've been very careful with how we...tag...to have a
...a buffering...we...make sure that we don't just end up creating a huge join string that they
...than right so this output object here is actually of type tag
helper output and when you...content that's...a
...for a reason that is of type tag...content thing it's a thing
...okay custom data structure that knows how to do the right is not string
...that string builders all the way down...it's a custom one that we make sure...over certain size and lots of
...okay so that's what should have to do right those...specific control if?
So, now I think I...to yet right so essentially twice now as
it twice now that's actually looks exactly like the before but just to prove it to you.
As repeated three times okay.
...encode moi.
Achievement...samoa.
...that's how easy to build...up of let's very quickly to commands...the last two minutes
two minutes one two-and-half minutes challenge I'm not saying we're going to finish you have two minutes twenty...
The demo...might be all right so I'm going to do a
...consul application...smoot smoothed press past
tense of might lighted saluted...smith...
...the common-law so I created a.
Everything in the column we are...consul up on over the project...file...created
a command forming that is itself...of inception going on here from a consul app
indian x is just...the next app web...any it's the same type of thing
...no difference the same thing that has a command configured two-run itself this is
my entry point you've declared...declared my entry point so I have a
...program cs with the static void...this case national static incidence...support instance
...now which is kinda nice so we can do things like depends injection indeo construct.
And, if I want to run this...the command-line now if I do a from
...going to run a particular wide let me go back here and you turn on the magic button.
Build this.
Ok.
Now actually make do anything I probably should write something out there consoled
I actually has a wma skiers something that I do have something nice
...that looks pretty good will come over here output that cm?
Okay, if I run that just prove that works.
...impressed...first...go off so now I've but, I'm building that out to the command-line
...to run this as a command from the command-line let's open
...folder so you just read as a command-line apple regular from...ran it from
...from the right so...would that for me I want to prove that this is actually standalone thing so I'm going to
do and...think about commands...commands like if you're familiar with node
you've got like grunt and express and things like that they are utilities commands that are
available, you know, possibly globally that you might want to use
...published those somewhere so you all could make commands that then we could go in
new get in to
our web applications and then use as utilities so I've gone into the
at folder inside artifacts...photo down here note there's my...file
...seventeen command so I can run consul seventeen dot
...from here and there's hello build running of the command-line but it's also a new
get package right so if I come back out here.
You have negative twenty seconds.
...my god...there is the nigger package now is not going to work because
I'm things and that has the same the files in it...the...file...that only but if you...believe me
...so that has the it has those files and I'm going...going...lights are coming up
...playing like music as somebody push stop on the recording
...it let's build almost...guys in...come over here...updated open
...union guys of left?
So, my new get package now has an app fold with the command by put that on you get...stole that with the
...I can...as a global...my system because it'll add this to my use a
...get of all tools of the command-line...I can run this many
...my system is...net deep dive edwards.